[MUSIC]
In this module we're
going to get technical,
as we teach you about the mechanics
behind the options market.
Some investors may be satisfied knowing
that call options are associated
with rising prices.
And that put options are associated
with falling prices.
But behind the scenes there's a lot
going on with how option prices move.
We'll start the module with a note about
some algebraic logic behind options
known as, put/call parity.
And then we're going to take
a deep dive into what factors
are important in determining
the price of an option.
We'll also help you visualize the payout
of an option trade with respect to
the price of the underlying asset.
And finally,
we'll walk you through a series of
risk variables known as option Greeks.
These values are important since they tell
investors how much or how little the value
of an option will change with respect to
changes in price, time, or volatility.
Let's get started.
[MUSIC]